Hey!
ちょっと
Come on!
Let me out!
出してくれない
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
I may be handsome, but putting me in a cage is in poor taste!
いくら俺が美少年だからって檻に入れる何て悪趣味
Just so you know, the heavens
favor these good looks.
言っとくけど この美貌は天に愛されてるんだからね
俺になにがあったら天罰が下るよ
If anything happens to me,
you'll suffer divine punishment!
天罰は我が龍がお決めになることだ
Our dragon decides who will be punished.
此奴等 やっぱり龍の血を持つ一族
The people of this clan
have the dragon's blood.
さて どうやって抜け出すか
How can I escape?
お姫さん達 捕まったりしてないだろな
I hope the others haven't been captured.
あ 左に見えますのは白龍様の...
To your left, you will see the White Dragon's-
Hey! Why are you taking a casual tour of the village?!
ちょっと そこなんでぶらり龍の里めぐり
Hey, Yun. How are you doing?
あぁユン 元気
I'm tied up quite well!
元気で縛られてるよ
I apologize for our treatment of your companion.
これはお連れ様にご無礼を
Let him out.
これ 出して差し上げなさい
But...
しかし
赤い髪のお客様だぞ
Our guest has red hair.
失礼しました
Excuse me!
What's going on?
なんなの
分からん
I don't know.
姫さんを見た途端 手のひらを返したように
The moment they saw the princess,
their attitude changed.
いや 姫さんと言うより...むしろ
No, they didn't seem to recognize her as a princess, but rather...
Episode 10:   Anticipation
先程の無礼をお許しください
Please forgive our insolence.
ここは神話の時代より戦乱の後
役目を終えた四龍の一人
Since the age of legends,
the White Dragon, one of the four dragons, has lived here,
after fulfilling his duty during the war.
白龍様が流れついて場所
Until now, we have eliminated the scoundrels who have come
これまで白龍様の力を手に入れようとする不届き者を
to claim the White Dragon's
power for their own.
我々は全て排除してきました
白龍様を守り その血を次に渡してゆく事が
Our clan's proud calling is
to protect the White Dragon,
ensuring his blood is passed on
to the next generation.
我が一族の使命であり誇り
他所者を易々とこの地に入れるわけには行かんのです
We do not readily allow outsiders into this land.
あんたらの事情は分かったが
I understand your situation, but...
なんだ これは
What is this about?
Red hair!
赤い髪 赤い髪だ
She has red hair!
It's so beautiful!
何と美しい
ハク 聞いた 美しいって
Hak, did you hear?
They called me beautiful.
Yeah, your hair.
髪がね
確かに珍しいけど 何ここ 赤髪信仰かなにか
It is unusual, but do the people here worship red hair or something?
我々にとって赤い髪は特別な思い入れがあるのですよ
Red hair evokes special
memories within our clan.
初代白龍様は赤い髪の主に仕えておられたから
The first White Dragon served
a red-haired master.
I hated my hair.
私 この髪嫌いだったのに
そんなもったいない
You mustn't say such things!
貴方は神官様のお導きでこの地を訪れたと言う
You were sent here by the priest.
もしや 貴方こそが 我々が待ち望んだ方かもしれない
You may be the one we've been waiting for.
違うかもしれない
But you may not be.
If she isn't, what will you do to us,
now that we know of this place?
違ったらどうするのさ この土地を知った俺等は
ともかく白龍様にお会いになってください
In any case, you must meet the White Dragon.
Hey! You hesitated too long!
長い 間が長いよ
Hey, Thunder Beast. Protect me.
ね 雷獣 守ってよね
If it comes down to it, protect me, okay?
もしもの時は守ってよね
どうしようかな
I don't know.
その白龍様ってのはどう特別なの
What makes the White Dragon so special?
この里の人間は皆白龍の子孫なんでしょう
Aren't all these villagers the White Dragon's descendants?
That's right.
そうです
しかし白龍様の力を持つお方はこの里でたった一人
However, only one villager possesses the power of the White Dragon.
右手に龍を宿してお生まれになるのです
He is born with a dragon
inside his right hand.
今朝はなぜだか妙に右手が疼くな
For some reason, my right hand has been throbbing this morning.
出会え 出会え
Quickly, quickly!
白龍様のお手が
The White Dragon is injured!
It isn't serious! Don't make such a fuss over it!
大事ない 大事ないから 大袈裟にするな
心の蔵が潰れるかと思ったわ
I almost had a heart attack.
大事なお手におけがでもあったのかと
I thought you had injured your precious hand.
其方はなんでも大袈裟にし過ぎだ
You always make such
a big deal of everything.
Since I was young,
幼い頃から
私の力が外部の人間の手に渡らないように守ってきた
you've protected me, to prevent my power from falling into outside hands.
本来なら私が其方等を守るべきなのに
But in truth, I should be
the one protecting you.
なにを仰います
What are you talking about?
You possess the power of the gods.
白龍様は神の力を持つお方
You are our pride and reason for living.
我々の誇り 生きる希望
You shine brighter than all the White Dragons that came before you.
特に貴方様は歴代のどの白龍様より美しく輝いておられる
だが どうにももどかしい
But I'm growing impatient.
此の力は何時 何の為に使えば良いかと
When am I supposed to use this power?
And for what purpose?
その時が来たらそのお方の為に
When the time comes,
you will use it for that person.
今は亡きお父上お母上も見守ておいてでしょう
Your late father and mother
watch over you now.
It's possible this era doesn't need your power.
そのお力はもしかしたらこの時代では不要なのかもしれぬ
しかし次の更に次の白龍様がきっと
However, I'm sure the next White Dragon and the one after that
will also use it to protect their masters, where you, perhaps, could not.
守るべき主の為にお使いになられる 貴方様の分まで
次の白龍だと
The next White Dragon?
You need only stay in the village and not worry about anything.
貴方様はなにも心配なさらず里に居てくだされば良い
守るべき主とは何時現れるのだ
When will the master I must protect appear?
早く会いたい 私を必要としてくれる主に
I want to meet the master who needs me soon!
ところで白龍様
By the way, White Dragon...
白龍様は御年二十歳におなりじゃったかの
you turned twenty this year, didn't you?
Jump
Yes, in fact.
そうだが
By now, you're old enough
to have a few wives.
そろそろ奥方が何人が居てもおかしくない年頃だの
Just one is enough.
一人でよい一人で
You don't have even one!
一人もおらんのじゃが
もう里には白龍様のお気に召す娘はおろんぞよ
Do you dislike all the girls in the village?!
早く 早く 我が主よ
Hurry. Please hurry, my master!
今朝は何やら騒がしいな
The village is awfully lively this morning.
Yes, it seems some outsiders have arrived.
外からの侵入者が出たようで
なに 即刻排除せんか
What? They must be eliminated immediately!
But apparently, they're rather unusual.
それがとても珍しい方らしくて
里の中心でちょっと騒ぎに
People are fussing over them
in the middle of the village.
Did they invite them in?
易々と招き入れたのか
でも可愛らしい女子だとか
But I heard there's a cute girl with them.
So what?
それがどうした
女の刺客など もっとも油断ならんではないか
We must be especially careful
of female assassins!
I'm going!
私が出る
White Dragon!
白龍様
この力 せめて里を守る為 役立てて見せる
I will, at least, use my power
to protect this village!
What's wrong, Princess?
どうした姫さん
途方もないわね
It's extraordinary.
Huh?
白龍の力を持つ子が一族の中から生まれると
When a child is born with the power of the White Dragon,
the dragon's blood disappears
from the previous White Dragon.
程なくして先代白龍の血は失われるんだって
そうしていつの日かまた龍の力が必要とされる時まで
The bloodline must be maintained
until the dragon's power is needed again.
血を繋いでいかなきゃいけないのよね
私 そんな力を借りに来たのね
I came to borrow that power.
やめとく
Should we give up?
ハク
Hak!
剣 貸して
Lend me your sword!
決めた事よ 後戻りなんてしない
I've made my decision.
I won't turn back.
But if the White Dragon won't help us,
you'll have to train me more!
でも白龍がダメだったら 私をもっと鍛えてね
侵入者は何処へ
Where are the intruders?
あそこか
There they are.
How dare you throw the village into confusion, scoundrels?
不届き者め 里を混乱に陥れるなど
I will tear you apart with my claws!
この爪で引き裂いてくれる
そこの女
You, woman!
Red hair?
赤い髪
What is this?
なんだ
My arm!
腕が
血が逆流するようだ
It feels like my blood is flowing backward!
You are now our other halves.
これより お前達は我々の分身
緋龍を主とし命の限りこれを守り
You will serve Hiryuu as your master, protecting him with your lives.
これを愛し 決して裏切るな
You will love him and never betray him.
このお方が このお方こそ求め続けた
This person... This is the one I have longed for.
My master.
我が主
White Dragon!
白龍様...
キジャ
Ki-ja...
神話の時代 四龍の戦士は緋龍王を守る為生まれた
In the age of legends, the dragon warriors were born to protect King Hiryuu.
また再び王は現れ お前の力を必要とするだろう
The king will appear again
and require your strength.
父上 何時になれば 私の王は現れるでしょう
Father, when will my king appear?
会えば分かる
When you meet him, you'll know.
お前の血が王を探します
Your blood will seek the king.
お前の白龍としての血が
The blood of the White Dragon.
お前は眩い光を見るだろう
You will see a dazzling light.
その時こそ 旅立ちの時だ
That is when you must depart.
White Dragon!
白龍様...
大丈夫
Are you all right?
Look! The White Dragon's hand...
見ろ 白龍様のお手が
父上
Father...
血を守り 一族を守り続けた歴代白龍達よ
Generations of White Dragons
who protected our blood and clan...
感謝します
I am grateful!
あの 白龍
Um, White Dragon?
はい 私は古より受け継がれし白き龍の血を引く者
Yes, I have inherited
the ancient dragon's blood.
お待ちしておりました 我が主よ
I have been waiting for you, my master!
主
Master?
なんの事
What are you talking about?
おめでとうございます 白龍様
Congratulations, White Dragon!
漸く我らの王が現れますね
Our king has finally appeared!
王？
King?
姫さんが王なんだとよ
They think you're the king.
赤い髪だから緋龍王だと思ってんのかも
Maybe they think you're King Hiryuu because you have red hair.
我が主よ
My master...
Huh?
宜しければお名前を
Please tell me your name.
ヨナ
Yona.
ヨナ...様
Lady Yona...
この人が白龍
This person is the White Dragon.
白銀の髪に透き通るような白い肌
He has silver hair and skin so pale
that it's almost transparent.
人ではない見たい
He doesn't seem human.
貴方綺麗ね
You're beautiful.
Not at all.
とんでもありません
ヨナ様の方が神々しいお姿で
You look far more divine.
Oh, my!
Oh, my...
あら 嫌だ
私 貴方の王でも主でもないわよ
I'm not your king or master.
Huh?
私は自分と仲間を守る為に
I'm a scoundrel who seeks the power of the gods
to protect herself and her friends.
神の力を欲しがる不届き者
Hey! Don't tell him that.
ちょ...黙っとこうよ そう言う事は
I'm traveling in order to find
the other three dragons, as well.
他の三人の龍も手に入れようと旅をしてるの
I ask that you grant me your power first.
最初に貴方の力を借りたい
いいかしら
Would that be all right?
光栄の極みにございます
There is no greater honor.
貴方が誰であろうと どんな目的であろうと
私は今から貴方の龍です
No matter who you are,
or what your goals may be,
I am now your dragon.
That is what the blood inside me says.
私の中の血がそう告げているのです
お爺共 私は直ちに旅立つ 我が主とともに
Elder, I will leave immediately with my master.
Yes, sir.
はい
What are you saying?!
何を言っておるのじゃ
まずは宴じゃ
We must throw a banquet first!
Prepare a banquet to celebrate King Hiryuu's revival!
緋龍王復活の宴だよ今は
Y-Yes, ma'am.
は はい
赤毛髪の王 お待ちしておりました
Red-haired king, we have been waiting for you.
その燃えるように美しき赤い髪
Your beautifully blazing red hair,
wise and lovely eyes, and smooth skin...
愛くるしくも聡明な瞳 すべすべのお肌...
じゃないのが痛ましい
I regret that you do not have these things.
あ 驚いた
Well, this is a surprise.
イクスの予言通りだけど
Ik-su's prophecy was right,
but I didn't think he'd join us that easily.
まさか あんなにすんなり仲間になってくれるとは
When I told him I'm a princess,
he was surprised.
姫だって話したら向こうもびっくりしてたしね
不届き者なんて言っちゃって
You called yourself a scoundrel.
本当だもの 彼に嘘は嫌だったし
Well, it's true. I didn't want to lie to him.
そして此奴がずっとニタニタしてて気持ち悪かった
And that guy was creeping me out,
grinning the whole time.
I'm not grinning.
別に
姫さんが神に喧嘩売る様な事言うから 楽しくて
I was just excited to hear the princess pick a fight with a god.
まだハクの皮肉
Are you being sarcastic again?
Of course not!
かさか
My right arm and body are still hot.
まだ右腕が 体が熱い
あのお方を見た途端
The moment I saw her,
all the blood in my body boiled.
全身の血が沸騰し 龍の声が魂に響いた
The dragon's voice echoed in my soul.
幼い頃から伝えられていた一族の悲願
Since I was a child, I've been told
of my clan's greatest hope.
数千年の時を経て 私に託された使命
The calling entrusted to me
over a thousand years ago.
父上 どうか見守っていて下さい
Father, please watch over me.
失礼
Excuse me.
Huh?
なっ 無礼者
Insolence!
白龍の城に無断で上がり込むとは
How dare you enter the White Dragon's dwelling without permission?
Yeah, sorry.
あ 悪い悪い
What are you doing?
何をしている
旅に役立ちそうなもん 調達しにきたんだが
I came to get any stuff that might
help us on our journey.
Do you have anything?
何がある
ほれ
Here.
Huh?
You're so generous, White Dragon.
気前いいね 白龍様
Take this, and leave the village.
これを持って 里から去れ
Huh?
I appreciate your efforts in the past.
これまでご苦労
これから先 姫は私がお守りする故 帰っていいぞ.
I will protect the princess from
now on, so you may leave.
Huh?
He's back.
戻ってきた
なんかすげぇ雲行き怪しいよ
This looks pretty ominous.
どうしたの
What's wrong?
姫さん 此奴はダメだ 他を当たろう
Princess, we can't use him.
Let's find someone else.
You must leave! I can protect
the princess myself!
其方こそ去れ 姫様は私一人で十分だ
温室育ちの坊ちゃんに外の世界なんて無理無理
A sheltered kid couldn't handle
the outside world.
Princess, why is such a boor escorting you?
姫様 なぜこのような粗暴な者が護衛なのですか
何があったのさ
What happened?
白龍様は俺に金やるから帰れと仰るんだ
The White Dragon said
he would pay me to leave.
And what's that bulge on your stomach?
で その腹の出っ張りは
メタボかな
Maybe I'm getting fat.
Protecting the princess is
the duty of the four dragons.
姫をお守りするのは四龍の役目
四龍でもない者は帰れ
Those who are not dragons should leave!
No!
いや
ハクは私の幼馴染で
Hak is my childhood friend.
Since I left the castle and ended up alone,
he's been with me.
城を出てからもひとりになってからも見捨てず側にいてくれたの
大事な人なの
He's important to me.
I want Hak with me!
ハクは一緒じゃなきゃ嫌
Ha
まぁ ね ほら
Well, you know...
Happy
つぅ訳よ
That's that.
Happy
Really Happy
しょうがねぇな
Happy
Really Happy
It can't be helped.
Happy
Really Happy
これは返却
I'm returning this.
姫がそう仰るなら
If you insist, Princess.
でにね 白龍も必要よ
But I need you too.
Otherwise, Hak will die protecting me.
だってこのままだとハク 私を守って死んじゃうもの
だから白龍はハクが死なない様に守ってほしいの
I want you to protect me,
so he won't die.
I see.
なんだそう言う事でしたか
That's how it is?
この者が弱いから私に救いを
You sought my help because he's weak?
Leave it to me. I will protect you and this man.
お任せを
姫様はもちろん この者は私が守ってやります
Huh?
結構だ
No, thank you.
白蛇如きに守って貰う程落ちちゃいねぇんで
I haven't fallen so far that I need to be protected by a white snake.
A white snake?
白蛇 其方 神聖なる龍を蛇だと
Did you just call the sacred dragon a snake?
This is gonna be a pain.
面倒くさい
これまで四人の白龍様をお育てした年月
Up to now, I have raised four White Dragons.
How many tears have I shed
every time I imagined this day?
幾度 今日と言う日を想像し その度に涙した事か
Yes, ma'am.
はい
これ
Hey!
この様なめでたい席で泣くでない
Don't cry on such a joyous occasion.
は はい
Y-Yes, ma'am.
白龍様
White Dragon...
I said that you all didn't have to see me off.
皆 見送りはせずともよいと申したはず
This is too much!
そんな あんまりです
We didn't think you would leave so soon!
出発はもっと先だと思っておりました
何を言う
What are you saying?
お仕えする主が現れたのだぞ
My master has appeared.
その方が我が力を必要とされているのだ
She needs my power.
歴代の白龍が今 この時の為に残してきた力を
The power that generations of White Dragons have passed down for this very day.
白龍様
White Dragon...
旅立ちの日まで皆に甘えていては天罰が下ろう
If I let you spoil me on the day I depart,
I will incur the wrath of the heavens.
白龍様が戻られるまでこの里の守りは我らに
Until you return, we will protect this village.
I'm counting on you.
頼んだぞ
里が安泰であれば 万が一私が死んでも
Even if I die, a new White Dragon will be born,
また新たな白龍の御子が誕生するであろうからな
as long as the village remains secure.
そんな事仰らないでください
Don't say such things!
You'll make us cry!
泣いちゃうぞ
You idiot, White Dragon!
白龍様のバカ
I-I'm sorry.
す すまない
白龍様
White Dragon!
Granny.
この握り飯を持っていきなされ
Take these rice balls with you!
道中 冷えるであろう ばばの作って外套と着替えじゃ
You'll get cold on your journey.
Wear these coats I made for you.
Also, here's ten years' worth of medicine,
and a serum to preserve your good looks!
後 薬十年分とその美貌を保つための美容液
Take this beauty with you too!
お供に一匹 持ってけ 泥棒
Granny, I can't hold all this!
ばば 持てぬ持てぬ
ばばよ
Granny.
では 暫らく留守にする
I'll be gone for a while.
The elders will take care of the village.
お爺達に村の事は任せてあるから
Who decided that without asking me?
わしな何も聞いておらぬぞ
留守を預かるのは里の長老であるばばの役目であろう
As the village's oldest member,
it's my responsibility to look after it.
しかしばば また目を悪くしたと聞いたが
But I heard your eyesight has gotten worse.
わしがこの里で一番ピチピチですぞ
No one in the village is healthier than me.
確かに元気は認めるが
You certainly are energetic.
But...
だが
張り合いがないわ
This is discouraging.
明朝 白龍様を叩き起こす事が もう出来んとは
Tomorrow morning, I won't be able to wake you.
Our clan's greatest hope has come true, but I didn't think it'd be so sudden.
一族の悲願が叶ったと言うのに
まさかこんなに 急だとは
ばば 顔を上げよ
Granny, lift up your head.
ばばは父上や母上より長くともに過ごし
I've spent more time with you
than with my parents.
私の成長を見守ってくれた
You watched over me as I grew.
You are my dear granny.
私の大切なばばだ
Even from distant lands, I will pray for everyone's happiness, as well as yours.
遠く離れた地からでも 私は皆とばばの幸せを願おう
だからばばも 体を労わって穏やかにすごされよ
You should rest your body
and live a quiet life.
Inexcusable!
聞き捨てならん
You make it sound as though I have only a few years left to live.
まるでばばが後数年で死ぬ様な言い様だの
ばばはまだまだ生きたりぬ
I haven't lived long enough yet.
白龍様がお役目を終えて戻られる時
Once you fulfill your duty and return,
わしは先頭でお出迎えしますぞ
I'll be the first to welcome you home.
必ずしますぞ
I promise!
何年先でも 盲いた目でも
No matter how many years pass, even if I'm blind,
I will always be able to see your radiance.
白龍様の輝きがわしには見えるのだ
お役目を果たして 必ず戻られよ
You must fulfill your duty and return.
これからどっち行こうか
Which way should we go now?
ユン イクスから何か聞いてない
Yun, did Ik-su tell you anything?
何も こっからは手掛かりなし
No, I have no leads from here.
What's wrong? Your eyes are red.
どうした 目赤いぞ
Shut up!
うっさい
困ったな
This is a problem.
四龍をお探しですよね
You're looking for the other dragons, aren't you?
Yes.
I can detect those who possess
the power of the dragons.
私 四龍の力を持つ者の気配 分かりますよ
本当
Really?
Yes.
微弱ではありますが 我々四龍は兄弟の様なものです
Though the link is faint, the four dragons are something akin to siblings.
古より遠く離れていても 血で呼び合うのです
Since ancient times, our blood has called out
to one another across great distances.
もっとも私も会った事ないのですが
I've never met them, though.
How convenient!
それ凄い便利
便利
Convenient?
Well, for now, let's start down the mountain.
よしゃ とりあえず山を降りるか
そういえば
By the way...
ね白龍 貴方の名前は
White Dragon, what's your name?
Everyone calls you "White Dragon," but that isn't your name, is it?
皆白龍様って呼ぶけど
白龍って名前ではないわよね
名前で呼んでも構わない
Can I call you by your name?
父上と母上しか呼ばない名は
もう呼ぶ者は居ないと思っていた
I thought no one would use the name my parents gave me ever again.
キジャ とお呼びください
Please call me "Ki-ja."
キジャ
Ki-ja.
いい名前ね
That's a nice name.
早く もたもたしてると置いてっちゃうよ
Hurry up! If you keep dawdling,
we'll leave you behind!
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
不用意に触れぬ方が良いぞ
You should be careful what you touch.
この力 私でさえ抑えが効かぬ
Not even I can restrain this power.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 11:
次回 暁のヨナ 第十一話
Episode 11:   The Dragon's Claw
龍の爪
The Dragon's Claw.